Guide to the James Gates Percival Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1800-1854; Series I; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  - Geography
    - 352. "The Varieties of the Human Race", circa 1825 (Box 4, Folder 103)
      Two drafts of the appendix, for his revised edition of Sir Richard Phillips's A Geographical View of the World, accompanied by corrected page proofs.
    - 353. General Distribution of the Animal Kingdom into Four Great Divisions, circa 1835 (Box 4, Folder 104)
      Autograph manuscript of material used for his 1836 revised edition of Sir Richard Philips's The Wonders of the World.
    - 354. A System of Ethnography. Proposal for a publication which never materialized, undated (Box 4, Folder 105)
      On reverse: A System (Outline) of the Geography of History.
    - 355. History of the Eruption of Etna Translated from the Italian of Ferrara, circa 1835 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - 356. Geography notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 107)
      Autograph manuscript fragments of notes probably used for his revised edition of Sir Richard Philips's The Wonders of the World or A Geographical View of the World.
  - Other Topics
    - 357. Webster's Dictionary, undated (Box 4, Folder 108)
      Percival's autograph manuscript notes (fragments) used in its revision.
    - 358. Botany lectures and botany notes taken on field trips around New Haven, 1819-1822 (Box 4, Folder 109-110)
    - 359. Prolegomena Intended as an Introduction to the Study of Therapeutics & Materia Medica, [1820?] (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - 360. Outline of a paper on science for the American Journal of Medicine, 1823 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - 361. "Chemical Apparatus and Instruments with the Agents and Reagents Necessary for a Course of Chemistry &c." by James Cutbush, 1820 Feb (Box 4, Folder 113)
      Autograph manuscript by Cutbush, dating from his position as professor at West Point, and used by Percival.
    - 362. Synod of Lothian & Tweeddale, 1802 (Box 4, Folder 114)
      Autograph manuscript list of the towns making up the various Presbyterian synods in Scotland.
    - 363. Knox's Elegant Extracts, circa 1826 (Box 4, Folder 115)
      Autograph manuscript notes used in Percival's 1826 edition of Elegant Extracts by Vicesimus Knox.
    - 364. Military and Naval Engagements from the Commencement of the American Revolution to the Present Time, undated (Box 4, Folder 116)
      Prospectus of a proposed volume "not less than 600 pages octavo & illustrated by 48 engravings on wood."
    - 365. Notes on cities and regiments with names of officers making up the militias of the various states, undated (Box 4, Folder 117)
      The most complete lists are for Vermont, Massachusetts, Connecticut, and New York.
- Notebooks and Notes, 1807-1840; Series II; 1.46; (4 boxes)
  Series II is organized into two subseries: Notebooks and Notes; within those subseries material is arranged by the consecutive numbers assigned by library staff.
  The series consists of a set of volumes in which Percival recorded his schoolwork, his poems, the books in his library, his expenses for trips taken, and notes on a variety of topics including linguistics. Prominent among them are his notes on the geology of Connecticut (which complements material in Box 3) and item number 420, which records of his dealings with his publishers.
  - Notebooks
    - 400. Seasons of New England. Winter[-Spring], 1811 (Box 5, Folder 118)
      Written at the age of 16. Series of long poems intended to include the four seasons, but not finished. Inscribed inside back cover: Philadelphia Dec 1815.
    - 401. Latin language notes and a bibliography of language of America, undated (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - 402. College notes on the sciences, 1810-1815 (Box 5, Folder 120)
      Contents: Mr. Silliman's private lectures on mineralogy. - Mr. Kingsley's lectures on history. - Husbandry. - Botany. - A view of the natural order of Linnaeus from the Encyclopedia Britannica. - System of Nature by Charles Line. - Additional genera from Shaw's General Zoology. - Murray's Chemistry. - Chemistry. - A course of Natural Science.
    - 403. College notes chiefly on the sciences, 1810-1815 (Box 5, Folder 121)
      Contents: Disputes and decisions by Dr. Dwight. - British poets. - Scotch airs and words adapted to them. - Diseases of children, Ives. - Dr. Ives on Materia Medica. - Dr. Smith on Nervous Diseases. - Botany notes.
    - 404. College notes on Benjamin Silliman's chemistry lectures 1-84, 1810-1815 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - 405. College notes and later linguistic bibliographies, 1810-1815 (Box 5, Folder 123)
      Contents: System of Rhetoric compiled from Blair's lectures and Dr. Dwight's remarks - Logic - Moral Philosophy - Dr. Dwight's advice. - Linguistic bibliographies - Disputations. - Mr. Kingsley on languages.
    - 406. College notes and linguistic bibliography, 1810-1815 (Box 5, Folder 124)
      Contents: Disputations - Linne's Systema Natura - Submersed algae from Dilwynn's Conservae. - System of theology from Vincent to Dr. Dwight - Wilson's Ornithology. - Linguistic bibliography.
    - 407. An Epitome of Wilson's Ornithology, undated (Box 5, Folder 125)
      Autograph manuscript notes on his readings.
    - 408. Science and linguistic notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 126)
      Contents: Zoology compiled from Shaw, Buffon, Pennant. - Mithradates vol. II, European languages vol. III, African languages - American languages.
    - 409. College notes and later linguistic notes and bibliography, 1810-1815 (Box 6, Folder 127)
      Contents: Mr. Day's Lectures on Natural Philosophy - Mithradates, vol. II - Linguistic notes. - F. Adelung's Uebersicht - Literature of languages.
    - 410. Geological notes and journals of his survey of Connecticut, circa 1840 (Box 6, Folder 128-130)
      Seven volumes of notes used for his Report on the Geology of the State of Connecticut (1842).
      Four notebooks gift of Chester R. Longwell (Yale PhD 1920), 1939.
    - 411. Geological notes on territory around New Haven: Derby, North Foxon, etc., 1840 (Box 6, Folder 131)
      Also containing 13 pages of geological maps.
    - 412. Survey notes for a canal or railroad in Connecticut, undated (Box 6, Folder 132)
      Two volumes with geological notes on the territory from New Haven to New London along the shoreline.
    - 413. Autograph manuscript notebook, probably of geological excursions in Connecticut, between June and August 1839 (Box 7, Folder 133)
      Bound with marbled-paper covers and green leather spine.
      Gift of Lemuel A. Welles (Yale 1893, MA 1895), 1939.
    - 414. Poems, undated (Box 7, Folder 134)
      Contents: To a young lady who had lent me Hayley's Triumphs of Temper. - Ode to melancholy. - Ode to fancy. - On viewing one summer evening the house of my nativity in a state of desertion. - Sonnets. - To a rose. - Ode on death. - Elegy. - Ode for the Fourth of July. - Ode to music. - On hearing a lady singing in the tow-r of Montevideo. - On the death of Miss __ who was drowned while bathing on Rockaway Beach. - Loch Maree. - On finding the Anamone Hepatica. - To the Gentiana Crinita the last flow-r of autumn. - To religion. - An imprecation. - Monody on Perry. - Other untitled verses. Many of these were first published in The Microscope, New Haven, 1820.
    - 415. Catalog of books in his library, sales records of his Poems, linguistic notes, etc., circa 1820 (Box 7, Folder 135)
      Contents: Catalogue of books. - Contents of Irving's Sketch Book. - Delineation of Scotland; extracts from the Beauties of Scotland. - Poem to Scotland. - Sales record of his Poems. 1821 - Sismondi, Literature du midi de l'Europe. - Notes on Spanish, Portuguese, German, Danish, and Italian literature. - Ode von Goethe zum Herrn Byron. - Languages and alphabets. - Aikin's British poets. - Hazlett's British poets. - Alphabets used in Webster's Dictionary. - Botany notes. - Rules for printing Arabic. - Linguistic notes on Danish Swedish, Russian, English, Wallachian, Romaic, Bulgarian. - Questions on Polit. econ. - Scotch literati 1792 by William Creech. - Welch grammar.
    - 416. Medical lecture notes taken at the University of Pennsylvania, 1818 (Box 7, Folder 136)
      From Dr. Eli Ives' Materia Medica class; also notes of a journey through the Catskills.
    - 417. Science notes taken from his reading, undated (Box 7, Folder 137)
      Contents: The transactions of ye Linn. Soc. vol. 9. - Geological inquiries. - Aikin's Annual Review, vol. 7.
    - 418. Natural history notes taken on his reading, undated (Box 7, Folder 138)
      Contents: Summary of Buffon's History of animals. - Notices of works in Natural History from Ailin's Annual Review. - Review of Science of ye 18th cent. from Millar Retrospect. - Synopsis Avium Rari.
    - 419. Exercise book, 1807 Sep 11 (Box 7, Folder 139)
      School copy-book chiefly lists of books to be read.
    - 420. Records of books and publishing, 1825-1829 (Box 7, Folder 140)
      Catalog of books in his library in 1827; record of accounts, 1825-1829; lists of books purchased; record of financial dealings with publishers, 1826-1828.
      Purchased from Joseph Lindsey, 1953.
  - Notes
    - 450. An Historical Account of the Most Celebrated Voyages ... by William Mavor, undated (Box 8, Folder 141)
      Notes on Mavor's book
    - 451. College disputes of his junior and senior years, 1814-1815 (Box 8, Folder 142)
      Including: Blackstone and notes on law - Division and arrangement of sciences - Napoleon - Franklin - National university - Physical and moral causes of national greatness - Is the mind always active? - Divorces - Active and passive commerce - Religion is necessary to government - Moral or natural causes - Power of Christianity - Natural history - Theatres.
    - 452. Chronology of Scotch Airs: notes on four epochs of Scotch folk songs, undated (Box 8, Folder 143)
    - 453. Notes on humor in "Sign," "Cross readings," and proper names, undated (Box 8, Folder 144)
    - 454. Theoretical notes on music made while a member of the New Haven Sing-Song Club, undated (Box 8, Folder 145)
    - 455. Notes on religion and a sermon on Romans 10, undated (Box 8, Folder 146)
    - 456. Miscellaneous notes on various subjects not including sciences or linguistics, undated (Box 8, Folder 147)
    - 457. Notes on his reading on all subjects: linguistics, geography, sciences, history, etc., undated (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - 458. List of scholar's names dated Remsen, Dec. 26, 1800 (Box 8, Folder 149)
      On verso: students paid for "Wood and Board"
    - 459. Scraps, undated (Box 8, Folder 150)
      Purchased on the George B. Alvord Fund, 1963.
- Personal Papers, 1819-1851; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series III is organized by the consecutive numbers assigned by library staff.
  The series holds many of Percival's financial papers documenting his payments for room, board, clothing, laundry, and other expenses, including his agreement with the General Hospital Society of Connecticut, where Percival lived from 1843 through 1851. Prominent among the papers are records related to his large collection of books: almost one hundred leaves of book inventories, more than twenty leaves of organizational schemes for the volumes, over eighty receipts from booksellers in Philadelphia, New York, Boston, and New Haven between 1819 and 1841, and insurance papers covering the collection. Also here are agreements regarding his publications, and a few general financial records. Other records for his publications and library are in Series II, Box 7, folder 140.
  - 500. Agreement with the General Hospital Society of Connecticut, New Haven, circa 1843 (Box 9, Folder 151)
    For the rental of rooms in the east end of the hospital (incomplete).
  - 501. Agreement with Sidney Babcock for a volume of poems, 1842 Dec 28 (Box 9, Folder 152)
  - 502. Agreement with Sidney Babcock for a revised edition of Sir Richard Philips's The Wonders of the World, 1831 Nov 26 (Box 9, Folder 153)
    Removed from The Tablet. (New Haven, 1831); gift of Owen Franklin Aldis (Yale 1874), 1911.
  - 503. Articles of agreement with Nathan Whiting to prepare for publication a history of the United States as a continuation of Botta's History of the War of Independence, 1833 Jun 26 (Box 9, Folder 154)
  - 504. Agreement with S. Converse concerning the proof-reading of Noah Webster's dictionary, undated (Box 9, Folder 155)
  - 505. Agreement with Captain W. W. Cobb of the U.S. Army concerning his duties as an army surgeon, 1824 Nov 1 (Box 9, Folder 156)
  - 506. Subscriber lists for the 1823 edition of his poems, 1822-1823 (Box 9, Folder 157)
  - 507. Subscriber lists for the 1832 edition of his poems, 1831-1832 (Box 9, Folder 158)
  - 508. Coat of arms: explanation of the Percival family coat of arms, undated (Box 9, Folder 159)
  - 509. Pedigree of the Percival family: manuscript chart showing genealogy of Percival's ancestors, undated (Box 9, Folder 160)
  - 510. Will and testament, Berlin, Connecticut, 1829 Apr 7 (Box 9, Folder 161)
    Document making Eli Ives and George Hayward his executors and leaving his personal property first to his mother, Elizabeth Porter, and after her to the Medical Society of Connecticut.
  - 511. Book lists of books ordered and/or purchased for his library, undated (Box 9, Folder 162)
  - 512. Statement of books received from C. Wiley, 1823-1825 (Box 9, Folder 163)
  - 513. Notes toward the arrangement of books in his library, undated (Box 9, Folder 164)
  - 514. Receipts and bills for books purchased in New Haven, New York, Philadelphia, and Boston, 1819-1841 (Box 9, Folder 165)
  - 515. Book lists of foreign books many of which he purchased for his library, undated (Box 9, Folder 166)
  - 516. Receipts for German books purchased, 1823-1846 (Box 9, Folder 167)
  - 517. Receipts for clothing, furniture and household repairs, New Haven, 1822-1847 (Box 9, Folder 168)
  - 518. Receipts for rent and board in New Haven and Boston, 1822-1851 (Box 9, Folder 169)
  - 519. Receipts, miscellaneous, chiefly for laundry, wood, and coal., 1824-1847 (Box 9, Folder 170-171)
  - 520. Other financial papers, 1821-1847 (Box 9, Folder 172)
    Bank notes and deposits, stock receipts, and promissory notes of Percival, his mother Elizabeth Porter, and his brothers Oswin and Edwin. Also includes a statement of his financial condition giving reasons of his indebtedness of $1,500.
  - 521. Insurance policy of the Protection Insurance Company covering Percival's library in Berlin, Connecticut, 1829 Jul 1 (Box 9, Folder 173)
  - 522. A. H. Maltby & Co., agreement to furnish paper and printing for 1000 copies of Prometheus Part II, 1822 Oct 23 (Box 9, Folder 174)
  - 523. General Hospital Society of Connecticut, Prudential Committee, 1843 Jan 8 (Box 9, Folder 175)
    Lease for rooms in Hospital building, New Haven, for lodging, study, and storage of his library and minerals.
  - 524. Agreements with Samuel Walker of Boston, 1825-1834 (Box 9, Folder 176)
    For the publication of Percival's revisions of Vicesimus Knox's Elegant Extracts and Conrad Malte-Brun's A System of Universal Geography.
  - 525. Agreement with Samuel Griswold Goodrich, 1824 (Box 9, Folder 177)
    Agreement that Percival will prepare an abridged biographical dictionary with Ezra Sargeant's edition of John Lemprière's Universal Biography (1810) as the basis, dated December 17, with letter (formerly 627.7) of December 29 declining the job.
- Correspondence, 1816-1856; Series IV; 1.25; (4 boxes)
  Organized into three subseries: Letters from James Gates Percival; Letters to James Gates Percival; and Third-Party Correspondence; within those subseries material is arranged by the consecutive numbers assigned by library staff.
  Series IV contains a collection of correspondence to and from Percival which was acquired from various sources. Prominent among the correspondents are Dr. George Hayward of Boston, and Percival's publishers Sidney Babcock, Samuel G. Goodrich, and Samuel Walker.
  Publication references noted are to J. H. Ward, The Life and Letters of James Gates Percival (Boston: Ticknor and Fields, 1866).
  - Letters from James Gates Percival
    Several letters are drafts or copies kept by Percival.
    - 600. To Charles D. Archibald, 1851 (Box 10, Folder 178)
      Three letters, one containing a report on the Acadian coal mines, Londonderry, with diagrams.
    - 601.1. To R. S. Baldwin, circa 1841 (Box 10, Folder 179)
      Concerns his Report on the Geology of the State of Connecticut. Published in Ward, pp. 354-73, with date "about May 20, 1841."
    - 601.2. To Park Benjamin, 1835 Aug 31 (Box 10, Folder 180)
      Two notes, including "Lays" submitted for publication. On reverse of one, Russian poem with translation.
    - 601.3. To Mrs. M. Bruen, 1823 Jun 30 (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - 602.1. To W. S. Cardell, concerning the etymology of the verb "to be.", 1827 (Box 10, Folder 182)
      Signed: Philocujus.
    - 602.2. To L. J. Cist, 1837-1838 (Box 10, Folder 183)
      Accompanied by a letter to Cist from J. L. Penckes enclosing a Percival autograph (not present).
      Removed from his Poems (New York, 1823); gift of Owen Franklin Aldis (Yale 1874), 1911.
    - 602.3. To S. Converse, concerning Webster's Dictionary, 1827 Aug 28 (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - 602.4. To G. L. Cross, 1829 Apr 1 (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - 602.5. To Lewis G. Clark, 1841 Apr 5 (Box 10, Folder 186)
      To editor of the Knickerbocker, New Haven, enclosing two songs for possible publication; negative photostat of original letter in the Samuel Rossiter Betts Autograph Collection (MS 603, Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library).
    - 603. To Samuel Dickson, 1831 (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - 604.1. Fragment to Mr. Editor, undated (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - 604.2. To William W. Ellsworth, 1840 Jun 17 (Box 10, Folder 189)
      Concerns his geological survey and gives the resolutions for 1837 and 1838.
    - 604.3. To A. Esty, 1853 Nov 28 (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - 606.1. To the Rev. Mr. Samuel Gilman, 1822 (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - 606.2. To Dr. H. Gridley, 1847 Mar 2 (Box 10, Folder 192)
    - 607.1. To George Hayward, 1829 Nov 28 (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - 607.2. To Frederic Stanhope Hill, 1827 Oct 11 (Box 10, Folder 194)
      Including poems and translation for publication in "The Memorial."
    - 607.3. To Anan Hine, 1838 Aug 13 (Box 10, Folder 195)
      On reverse: Czech and Bohemian linguistics.
    - 607.4. A.L.S. to Hon. S. T. Hosmer, 1824 Jan 13 (Box 10, Folder 196)
      Removed from J. H. Ward, The Life and Letters of James Gates Percival (Boston, 1866); gift of Owen Franklin Aldis (Yale 1874), 1911.
    - 607.5. To Dr. Samuel G. Howe, 1832 Dec 16 (Box 10, Folder 197)
      Including the manuscripts of his sonnet series, "Slavonia."
    - 608.1. To Dr. Eli Ives, 1816, undated (Box 10, Folder 198)
    - 611. To J. W. Lapham, 1853 Feb 26 (Box 10, Folder 199)
    - 612.1. To Robert McMenomy, 1827 Dec 3 (Box 10, Folder 200)
      Concerns the purchase of six volumes of Dante.
    - 612.2. To George Morey, 1824 Jul 24 (Box 10, Folder 201)
      Published in Ward, p. 255.
    - 612.3. To L. K. Murdock, 1845 Jul (Box 10, Folder 202)
    - 613. New Haven Sing-Song Club, undated (Box 10, Folder 203)
      Six autograph manuscript communications "To the New Haven Sing-Song Club" describing German songs which he translated for them.
      One leaf purchased from the Carnegie Book Shop on the George B. Alvord Fund, 1951.
    - 615. To his brother Edwin Percival, undated (Box 10, Folder 204)
    - 617.1. To Rev. Edward Robinson, 1836 Feb 26 (Box 10, Folder 205)
      Addressed to "wetheste Frau", the first paragraph is in German, and the letter concerns the translation of German poetry. The letter is intended for Mrs. Robinson (Talvj).
    - 617.2. To John Arnold Rockwell, 1838 Oct 30 (Box 10, Folder 206)
    - 618.1. To H. Seifert, 1855 Feb 27 (Box 10, Folder 207)
    - 618.2. To S. M. Stone, undated (Box 10, Folder 208)
    - 618.3. To W. L. Stone, 1823 Feb 29 (Box 10, Folder 209)
      On reverse: fragment of a long poem.
    - 619.1. To George Ticknor, 1832 Jul 18 (Box 10, Folder 210)
      On reverse: list of French books; published in Ward, p. 325.
    - 619.2. To George Ticknor, 1843 Nov 15 (Box 10, Folder 211)
      Negative photostat of original letter in the Samuel Rossiter Betts Autograph Collection (MS 603, Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library).
    - 619.3. To Messrs Townsend, Fairbanks and Greenleaf Committee, undated (Box 10, Folder 212)
      Including five stanzas of poetry for publication.
    - 622.1. To A. Waldie, 1835 Apr 11 (Box 10, Folder 213)
      Removed from his Poetical Works, vol. 1 (Boston, 1859); gift of Owen Franklin Aldis (Yale 1874), 1911.
    - 622.2. To C. C. Washburn, 1855 Jan. 20 (Box 10, Folder 214)
    - 622.3. To Noah Webster, circa 1827 (Box 10, Folder 215)
      Concerns the Dictionary
    - 622.4. Four letters to Henry White, 1855 (Box 10, Folder 216)
      Two letters purchased from G. E. Thompson, 1926; two letters gift of Howard S. Mott, 1952.
    - 622.5. To the Assignee or executor of Charles Wiley deceased, 1826 Mar 20 (Box 10, Folder 217)
    - 622.6. To D. C. Williams, 1841 Jun 17 (Box 10, Folder 218)
      On reverse: nine stanzas of poetry.
    - 624. Five letters to J. Lawrence Yvonnet, 1822-1823 (Box 10, Folder 219)
      All published in Ward: June 11, 1822, pp. 95-100; June 26, 1822, pp.102-09; Apr. 17, 1823, pp. 153-57; June 14, 1823, pp. 159-63; July 18, 1823, pp. 166-73; Sept. 23, 1823, p. 176.
    - 626. Three letters to his mother Elizabeth Porter, 1823-1843 (Box 10, Folder 220)
    - 627.1-8. Seven notes and fragments to unidentified recipients, 1828-1834 (Box 10, Folder 221)
      627.2 is from the Daggett Autograph Collection; 627.3 quotes and translates from Aristophanes Frogs; 627.8 concerns linguistics. A final draft of 627.6 is in the Boston Public Library. 627.7 was moved to folder 525.
    - 628. Notes, fragments of letters, invitations, etc. containing fragments of poems, translations, linguistic notes, etc., undated (Box 10, Folder 222)
  - Letters to James Gates Percival
    Many of the letters in this section are from representatives of American institutions (including Yale and other colleges), learned societies, special committees, businesses, and governments but the letters were filed under the signer's name.
    - 650.1. Adair, Robert F., 1851 (Box 11, Folder 223)
    - 650.2. Adams, Charles Baker, 1846 (Box 11, Folder 224)
    - 650.3. Adams, James Turvill, 1844 (Box 11, Folder 225)
    - 650.4. Andrews, Ethan Allen, 1846 (Box 11, Folder 226)
      Gift of Joseph I. Lindsey, 1940.
    - 650.5. Archibald, Charles D., 1852 (Box 11, Folder 227)
    - 650.6. Augur, Hezekiah, 1840-1844 (Box 11, Folder 228)
    - 651.1. Babcock, Sidney, 1831-1855 (Box 11, Folder 229)
      One 1846 letter gift of Joseph I. Lindsey, 1940.
    - 651.2. Babcock, W. R., 1823 (Box 11, Folder 230)
    - 651.3. Bacon, Delia Salter, 1836 (Box 11, Folder 231)
    - 651.4. Baldwin, A. C., 1842 (Box 11, Folder 232)
    - 651.5. Baldwin, Christopher Columbus, 1834 (Box 11, Folder 233)
    - 651.6. Bailey, Ebenezer, 1833-1834 (Box 11, Folder 234)
    - 651.7. Barnard, Henry, 1838-1840 (Box 11, Folder 235)
    - 651.8. Barnes, J. S., 1839 (Box 11, Folder 236)
    - 651.9. Barstow, William Augustus, 1854-1855 (Box 11, Folder 237)
    - 651.10. Beck, Lewis Caleb, 1839 (Box 11, Folder 238)
    - 651.11. Belden, H., 1825 (Box 11, Folder 239)
    - 651.12. Benjamin, Park, 1835 (Box 11, Folder 240)
    - 651.13. Boardman, William W., 1836-1842 (Box 11, Folder 241)
    - 651.14. Brewster, James, 1841 (Box 11, Folder 242)
    - 651.15. Bronson, Arthur, 1822-1823 (Box 11, Folder 243)
    - 651.16. Bruen, Mrs., 1823 (Box 11, Folder 244)
      Contains subscription list.